Guide to the National Council of Jewish Women, Pittsburgh Section Records, 1894-2011 AIS.1964.40
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1943-1995; XVI.
  - Council Care, 1986-1988 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Council Care, 1989-1990 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Council Care, 1993-1995 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Council Care, Volunteer training, 1993 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Council Care, Management, 1993-1994 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Council Care, Alzheimer unit, 1982, 1985-1986 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Council Care, Insurance, 1983-1991 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Council Care, Lawsuits, 1983 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Council Care, Minutes, 1983-1992 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Council Care, Press releases, 1982-1983 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Council Woman, June 1964 - July/August 1979 (Box 64, Folder 12-13)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1986 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1988 (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 17-18)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Designer Dress Days, Newspaper clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Designer Dress Days, Publicity, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - Designer Dress Days, Public relations, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - Designer Dress Days, Chairs, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 23)
  - Designer Dress Days, David L. Lawrence Convention Center, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 24)
  - Designer Dress Days, Merchandise/warehouse, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 25)
  - Designer Dress Days, Money, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 26)
  - Designer Dress Days, Public relations, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 27)
  - Designer Dress Days, Staffing and volunteers, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 28)
  - Enriched Housing Project, 1993 (Box 64, Folder 29)
  - Evaluation of NCJW/JCC merger of Program for Elderly, 1978 (Box 64, Folder 30)
  - Friends Indeed, 1977-1985 (Box 64, Folder 31)
  - Friends Indeed (continued), 1977-1985 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Future planning, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - General public relations, 1984-1991 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Industrial League, 1943 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Logos (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Mitzvah Corps, 1994-1995 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - "My Voice Was Heard" (oral history), 1981 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - NCJW, Central District Convention, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - NCJW, Department of Publicity and Public Relations, 1980-1989 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - NCJW, Education, Social Action, and Service (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - NCJW, Joint Program Institute, 1981-1984 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - NCJW, Overall, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - NCJW, Research Institute, 1971-1974 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - NCJW, 75th Anniversary, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - New Members luncheon, 1990-1991 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Newletter, 1984-1989 (intermittent) (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - 90th Birthday Party, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - 95th Birthday Party planning meeting, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Oral history (general information), 1981-1994 (Box 65, Folder 19)
  - Press clippings, 1984-1985, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 20-21)
  - Programs, 1986 (Box 65, Folder 22)
  - Public Relations to National, 1986-1987 (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Programs, 1986 (Box 65, Folder 22)
  - Puppet show, 1983-1984 (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Race for the Cure, 1992-1995 (Box 65, Folder 24)
  - Russian Resettlement, 1990-1991 (Box 65, Folder 25)
  - Services to the Elderly Committee, 1991-1995 (Box 65, Folder 26)
  - Service to the Foreign Born, 1934, 1974, 1979, 1982 (Box 65, Folder 27)
  - Ship-a-Box, 1976-1979 (Box 65, Folder 28)
  - Single Women in Midlife (SWIM), 1978-1987 (Box 65, Folder 29-30)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1970 (Box 65, Folder 31)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1979-1980 (Box 65, Folder 32)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1980-1981 (Box 65, Folder 33)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1981-1982 (Box 65, Folder 34)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1982-1983 (Box 65, Folder 35)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1984-1985 (Box 65, Folder 36-37)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1985-1986 (Box 65, Folder 38)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1986-1987 (Box 65, Folder 39)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 40)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 41)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 42)
  - Survey evaluations, 1978-1980 (Box 65, Folder 43)
  - Survey and Evaluations Committee, 1991 (Box 65, Folder 44)
  - Task Force Volunteerism, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 45)
  - Thrift Shop, 1990-1991 (Box 65, Folder 46)
  - Tours, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 47)
  - Vice-President's Annual Report, 1995 (Box 65, Folder 48)
  - Vice-President's training, June 18, 1991 (Box 65, Folder 49)
  - Volunteer Recognition, 1960-1987 (Box 65, Folder 50)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 51)
  - White House Conference on Families, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 52)
  - Woman's Center and Shelter (Debra House), 1994-1995 (Box 65, Folder 53)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - "Everybody has a Story," Program from NCJW Pittsburgh Annual Meeting, 2007 (Box 114, Folder 1)
- Organizational Records, 1934-1989; XVII.
  Series XVII contains the Pittsburgh Section's administrative committees and activities, workshops, projects, and community and political involvement. This series primarily consists of materials dated from 1970 to 1997, however there are some records dating from the 1930s to the 1960s. Because these boxes were added to the collection later than 1964, many of the subjects in this series also have materials throughout the collection. All files are alphabetically arranged.
  - Abuse of Elderly, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Adolescent Pregnancy Watch, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Aging Council, 1960-1991 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1965-1984 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1978-1989 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Anathan House and Dedication, 1963-1988 (Box 66, Folder 6-7)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai Brith, 1983-1985 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Board Training and Workshops, 1959-1989 (Box 66, Folder 9-11)
  - Center for Research in Education of the Disadvantaged, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Child Care Community Services, 1972-1973 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Children and youth programs, 1980-1988 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Children's Council of Western Pennsylvania, 1985-1989 (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Children's Waiting Room at Family Court Project, 1979-1989 (Box 66, Folder 16-18)
  - Civil Rights Council of Allegheny County (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Commission for Women, 1980-1989 (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Community services, correspondence and questionnaires, 1978-1992 (Box 66, Folder 21-22)
  - Constitutional rights, 1976-1986 (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Council News, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - Day care and Day Care Research Project, 1973-1987 (Box 66, Folder 25-26)
  - Dress Designer Days, 1979-1989 (Box 66, Folder 27-34)
  - Domestic violence, 1989-1991 (Box 66, Folder 35)
  - Education desegregation, 1976-1980 (Box 66, Folder 36)
  - Energy Task Force, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 37)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1978-1992 (Box 66, Folder 38)
  - Extraordinary Tutoring Project (Box 66, Folder 39)
  - Fair Housing, 1979-1980 (Box 66, Folder 40)
  - Generations Together, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 41)
  - Gun control, 1968-1969 (Box 66, Folder 42)
  - Hands Across America, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 43)
  - Home Instruction Program for Pre-School Youngsters (HIPPY), 1986-1989 (Box 66, Folder 44-45)
  - Israel Affairs, Israel Day Parade, 1980-1989 (Box 66, Folder 46)
  - Israel Heritage Room, 1982-1987 (Box 66, Folder 47)
  - Jewish Community Center, 1983-1988 (Box 66, Folder 48)
  - Joint Program meetings, 1981-1987 (Box 66, Folder 49)
  - Joint Program, United Jewish Federation, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 50)
  - Justice for Children, 1972-1979 (Box 66, Folder 51-52)
  - KKK County Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 66, Folder 53)
  - Ladies Hospital Aid Society, 1988-1989 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Leadership development, 1976-1987 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - "My Voice Was Heard," copyright registration form, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - National Affairs, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1982-1985 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Oral History Project (Box 67, Folder 7-14)
  - Parenting Conference, 1980 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Pay Equity Conference, 1987-1989 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania Association for Volunteerism, 1987-1988 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Coalition to Prevent Nuclear War, 1983-1986 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Pittsburgh Conference on Soviet Jewry, 1980-1988 (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Police Banner Project, 1986-1988 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Pro-Choice position statement, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Program Department and study group, 1981-1984 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Public Affairs Department, 1974-1991 (Box 67, Folder 23-34)
  - Quota Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 67, Folder 35)
  - Renaissance Center, 1969-1988 (Box 67, Folder 36)
  - Research Institute for Innovation in Education, 1975-1989 (Box 67, Folder 37)
  - Russian Resettlement, 1934-1980 (Box 67, Folder 38-42)
  - Service to the Aged, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 43)
  - Squirrel Hill Urban Coalition, 1973-1989 (Box 67, Folder 44)
  - South Hills Branch newsletter, 1989-1990 (Box 67, Folder 45)
  - Soviet Jews, Women's Plea, 1988-1989 (Box 67, Folder 46)
  - Stay-at-Home Ball, 1983-1990 (Box 67, Folder 47-49)
  - Survey an Evaluation Committee, 1967-1988 (Box 67, Folder 50)
  - Single Women in Midlife (SWIM), 1987-1991 (Box 67, Folder 51)
  - Task Force on Volunteerism, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 52)
  - Thrift Shop Program, 1978-1989 (Box 67, Folder 53)
  - Volunteer Department, 1979-1990 (Box 67, Folder 54-56)
  - Western Pennsylvania Auxiliary for Exceptional People, 1975-1984 (Box 67, Folder 57)
  - Women's Center, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 58)
  - Women in Community Service (WICS), 1975-1989 (Box 67, Folder 59-60)
  - Women in organizations, 1978-1987 (Box 67, Folder 61)
  - Women in Renaissance II, 1983-1987 (Box 67, Folder 62)
- Council Journals, 1949-1954; XVIII.
  Series XVIII contains the two logbooks from the Council Lounge for Older People dating from 1949-1954. Each logbook includes daily and weekly narrative entries documenting various Council Lounge administrative activities and projects.
  - Logbook, 1949-1954 (Box 68, Volume 1-2)
- Publications and Papers, 1967-1976; XIX.
  Series XIX contains two copies of a 1967 NCJW publication, Where There's A Woman by Bernice Graziani. The book is a 75-year narrative and pictorial history of NCJW. Also included in this series is the dissertation by Ida Cohen Selavan, "The Columbian Council of Pittsburgh, 1894-1909: A Case Study of Adult Immigrant Education." Authored by Selavan in 1976, this paper was submitted to the Graduate Faculty in the School of Education in partial fulfillment of the requirements for a Doctor of Philosophy degree. The paper focuses on the NCJW Pittsburgh Section's development and activities concerning education and immigration between 1894 and 1909.
  - Where There's A Woman, 1967 (Box 68, Volume 3-4)
  - "The Columbian Council of Pittsburgh, 1894-1909: A Case Study of Adult Immigrant Education", 1976 (Box 68, Volume 5)
- Scrapbooks, 1944-1990; XX.
  Series XX consists of a total of 15 scrapbooks. Eight of the scrapbooks document various organizational activities and events of the NCJW Pittsburgh Section and two are dedicated to the South Hills Branch. Most of the scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, however some contain bulletins, letters, and photographs.
  - Publicity, miscellaneous, 1944-1961 (Box 68, Volume 6-7)
  - Stay at Home Ball (Box 69, Volume 1)
  - Anathan House, 1950-1960 (Box 69, Volume 2)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1976-1980 (Box 69, Volume 3-6)
  - NCJW, 1980-1983 (Box 70, Volume 1-3)
  - South Hills Branch, 1971-1990 (Box 70, Volume 4-5)
- Photographs and Slides, 1933-1990; XXI.
  Series XXI consists of various photographs of NCJW Pittsburgh Section members, activities, programs, parties, and local and national conferences and meetings. The photographs date from 1933 through the 1990s, however the bulk of the photographs are from the 1970s to the 1990s. Their primary focus is on activities related to the Organizational Records Series (Series XVII). All photographs are placed in alphabetical order according to subject.
  - Adult Program, 1980s (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Anathan House, 1970-1990 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Angel Ball, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1979-1992 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Bethesda Tutorial Program, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Birthday party, Dorothy Blumenthal, 1965 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Board Dinner, 1990 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, training, 1974-1990 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - "Bridges to History", early 20th Century (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - By-laws Committee, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - By Myself I'm A Book party, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Buildings, early 20th Century (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Bus tours, 1977-1984 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Cancer Dressing Program, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Chanukah Party, 1977-1978 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Child care, 1990s (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Children's Waiting Room, 1980-1990 (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - Community services, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 18)
  - Congressional, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 19)
  - Creative Drama Program, 1971-1972 (Box 71, Folder 20)
  - Council Care (some slides), 1980-1990s (Box 71, Folder 21)
  - County Commissioners, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 22)
  - Council Committees, meetings, and miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 23)
  - "Day in the Life of Israel", 1990s (Box 71, Folder 24)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1970s-1990s (Box 71, Folder 25-27)
  - Domestic violence, 1990s (Box 71, Folder 28)
  - Employee party, 1990s (Box 71, Folder 29)
  - Fashion show, 1990s (Box 71, Folder 30)
  - Friends Indeed, 1970s-1980s (Box 71, Folder 31)
  - George Gershwin with Pittsburgh Symphony Board members, 1933 (Box 71, Folder 32)
  - Governor Dick Thornburgh, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 33)
  - HIPPY Project, 1970s-1980s (Box 71, Folder 34)
  - Israel Day Parade, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 35)
  - Joint Program meetings, 1980s (Box 71, Folder 36)
  - Juvenile Court Council, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 37)
  - Leadership development, 1990s (Box 71, Folder 38)
  - Lifestyle Project, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 39)
  - Luncheons, miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 71, Folder 40)
  - Members, miscellaneous, 1980s-1990s (Box 71, Folder 41-43)
  - Membership Committee, 1970s-1990s (Box 71, Folder 44)
  - Membership party, 1977 (Box 71, Folder 45)
  - National Convention meetings, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 46)
  - Newsletter, 1990s (Box 71, Folder 47)
  - Ninety-fifth birthday party, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 48)
  - Norman Buffet, miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 49)
  - Oral history, 1970s (Box 71, Folder 50)
  - Parties, miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Past Presidents, 1990-1991 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Planning Committee, 1980s (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Politics, local, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Portraits, NCJW members, 1980s-1990s (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Presentations, 1972-1973 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - President's Luncheon, 1988-1989 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Pro-Choice Program, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Program meetings, 1970s-1990s (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Research Institute for Innovation in Education, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Russian parties, 1970s-1990s (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Russian Resettlement, 1970s-1990s (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Senior Adults, 1980s (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Ship-A-Box Program, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - South Hills Branch members, 1980s (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Speaker programs, miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Staff members (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Student Committee, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Study Group, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 21)
  - Summit Conference, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 22)
  - SWIM Program, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Tennis Fundraiser, 1990s (Box 72, Folder 24)
  - Thrift Store Program, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 25)
  - Training, 1977 (Box 72, Folder 26)
  - Tree of Life meeting, 1975-1976 (Box 72, Folder 27)
  - Volunteer of the Year, slides, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 28)
  - Volunteer Project, 1987-1988 (Box 72, Folder 29-31)
  - Volunteer Leadership course, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 32)
  - Washington, D.C. with Senator Arlen Spector, 1970s (Box 72, Folder 33)
  - Washington Institute, slides, 1986 (Box 72, Folder 34)
  - White House reception, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 35)
  - Young Associates, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 36)
- Awards, 1954-1993; XXII.
  Series XXII consists of various local and national awards and plaques given to NCJW Pittsburgh Section and individual members. Of importance are awards given to the Pittsburgh Section by the Governor of Pennsylvania and Mayor of Pittsburgh.
  - Anathan House Anniversary, letter of recognition by Solomon B. Freehof, 1983 (Box 72, Folder 37)
  - Benjamin Rush Award, 1960 (Box 72, Folder 38)
  - Commission for Women Commendation, Allegheny County, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 39)
  - Community Human Services Award, 1971-1979 (Box 72, Folder 40)
  - Day of the Working Parent Commendation, City of Pittsburgh, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 41)
  - Jewish War Veterans Award, Post #49, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 42)
  - National Approval Award, Learning Disabilities Project, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - National Approval Award, Library Service at the Jewish Historical Society, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - National Council of Jewish Women Week, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - National Council of Jewish Women Week, City of Pittsburgh, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - NCJW Annual Support Award, 1983, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 5-6)
  - NCJW Membership Award, National Convention, 1974-1975 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Proclamation, Mayor Lawrence of Pittsburgh, 1954 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Washington Institute Award, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 9)
- Organizational Records, 1947-1990; XXIII.
  Series XXIII consists of the Pittsburgh Section's organizational records. The bulk of the records are from 1970 to 1990. Again, since this is a later addition many of the materials in this series can be found throughout the collection.
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Study District and Areas, 1981 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Anathan House, Beginnings (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Anathan House, Y-IRC Committee, 1973-1976 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Anathan House, Y-IKC Committee merger, January 1, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Anathan House, Original renovations, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Anathan House, 20th Anniversary of Anathan House/10th Anniversary of NCJW/JCC merger of Senior Adult Programs, September 25, 1983 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - ANS, 1970-1980 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Dorothy Blumenthal (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Buncher family (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Business and Professional Group (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Central District, By-laws (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Central District, Newsletter, 1980 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Central District, Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Central District, Miscellaneous, 1980-1990 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - City Block Grant, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - College Age Group Program, 1968-1969, 1975 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Council Care, General, 1984-1995 (Box 74, Folder 17-20)
  - Council Care, Agreements, 1982-1993 (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - Council Care, Community Workshop, April 1991 (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - Council Care, Fundraiser, 1993-1994 (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Council Care, Management and minutes, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - Council Care, Public relations, 1987-1994 (Box 74, Folder 25)
  - Council Care, Range Planning Committee, 1991-1994 (Box 74, Folder 26)
  - Council Care, St. Clair, 1987-1994 (Box 74, Folder 27-28)
  - Councilettes (Box 74, Folder 29)
  - Evening Division, 1960-1980 (Box 74, Folder 30)
  - Juniors, 1947-1949 (Box 74, Folder 31)
  - Junior Volunteer Corps (Box 74, Folder 32)
  - Life memberships, 1970-1980 (Box 74, Folder 33)
  - Male memberships 15/15, 1986 (Box 74, Folder 34)
  - Membership recognition for 50-year members, 1977 (Box 74, Folder 35)
  - Membership recruitment, 1981-1988 (Box 74, Folder 36)
  - Paid-up membership meetings, 1978-1988 (Box 74, Folder 37-40)
  - Program Department, study groups and workshops, 1976-1979 (Box 74, Folder 41)
  - Program meetings, 1979-1988 (Box 74, Folder 42-46)
  - Program meetings, Wolf Blitzer, September 24, 1981 (Box 74, Folder 47)
  - Program meetings, David Cohen, September 14, 1989 (Box 74, Folder 48)
  - Program meetings, Leslie Gelb, September 30, 1982 (Box 74, Folder 49)
  - Program meetings, Jeff Greenfield, September 23, 1980 (Box 74, Folder 50)
  - Program meetings, John Simon (Box 74, Folder 51)
  - Program meetings, Madame Wellington, January 20, 1981 (Box 74, Folder 52)
  - Program meetings, Intermarriage, March 5, 1981 (Box 74, Folder 53)
  - Program meetings, The Jews in America, 1989 (Box 74, Folder 54)
  - Reproductive Freedoms, Pittsburgh Jewish Organizations/DC rally, 1989 (Box 74, Folder 55)
  - Senior Council, 1989 (Box 74, Folder 56)
  - South Hills Branch, 1975-1992 (Box 74, Folder 57-59)
  - South Hills Branch-Speeches, installations, and acceptances, 1977-1979 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - South Hills Branch-Vice President's Personal Personnel Handbook, 1980, 1988 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Speeches (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - State Office of Volunteers, 1977-1979 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Volunteer training, LHA, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Young Associates, 1983-1984 (Box 75, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1970-1989; XXIV.
  Series XXIV contains photographs of various NCJW Pittsburgh Section and South Hills Branch activities, members, and programs. On photographs where the exact date is not known a general date is given, such as "1970s." Also, names of those pictured can be found on the back of the photographs.
  - Council Care, 1970s (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Eleanor Saroker and Harriet Braum, 1970s (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - General, 1970-1978 (Box 75, Folder 9-10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1972 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Designer Dress Days and PCIV Coffee, 1977-1978 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Hunt 85th birthday party, January 1979 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Annual meeting, 1980 (Box 75, Folder 16)
  - United Nations Meeting, October 25, 1983 (Box 75, Folder 17)
  - Ladies Hospital Aid, 1983 (Box 75, Folder 18)
  - Stay-At-Home Sale, 1983 (Box 75, Folder 19)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball, 1983 (Box 75, Folder 20)
  - 20th Anniversary of Anathan House/10th Anniversary of NCJW/JCC merger of Senior Adult Programs, September 1983 (Box 75, Folder 21)
  - General, 1983-1984 (Box 75, Folder 22-26)
  - Fran Lebowitz Meeting, 1984 (Box 75, Folder 27)
  - Family Court Waiting Room, 1985 (Box 75, Folder 28)
  - Puppet Show, 1985 (Box 75, Folder 29)
  - Council Care II, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
  - Family Court Waiting Room and Senior Adult Lunches, December 1986 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Family Court Waiting Room, January 1, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meeting, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 5-6)
  - Designer Dress Days, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - National Conference, March 20-24, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - JPI, Washington, D.C., 1985 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Friends Indeed, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Sally Jesse Raphael, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Council Care, December 1986 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - SWIM, December 1986 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 76, Folder 14-15)
  - Washington Institute, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Council Care I, II, and III, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - S.H. Valento Recognition, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Fox Chapel Yacht Club Workshop, May 1987 (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Nora Ephron, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - Regina Stern, January 1987 (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Designer Dress Days Warehouse Opening, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball Kick-off Luncheon, January 1987 (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - Stay-At-Home Ball, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 24)